Guide to the Oversize Manuscripts Collection 1648-2018 MS OS
New-York Historical Society
Oversize manuscripts collection
1648-2018
New-York Historical Society
MS OS
4.2 Linear feet
This collection is an "artificial collection'' of unrelated materials that are stored together due to their large size. The collection is organized into two series. Series I consists of oversize items that were donated or acquired individually, and are not part of a larger collection. This series is arranged by date. Series II is composed of oversize items that were accessioned as part of larger manuscript collections, but are physically located in oversize storage. These items are organized alphabetically by the name of the originating collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection is an "artificial collection", meaning that it contains a variety of unrelated materials that have been grouped together according to size in order to facilitate storage and access. The collection includes a wide variety of formats and topics. It holds items of unrelated provenance that include: correspondence, official documents (deeds, wills, bonds, etc.), certificates, maps, drawings, blueprints, and photostats. While the majority of the materials are from New York state, there are also many documents originating in other areas of the United States. Because the dates of the materials in the collection range from 1648-1998, the collection encompasses a particularly large span of American history.
Many of the folders in the collection relate to important historical figures, including former presidents of the United States, military leaders, and influential New York families. Documents signed by the following presidents can be found in the collection: George Washington, Thomas Jefferson, James Monroe, James Madison, Andrew Jackson, Martin VanBuren, James K. Polk, Millard Fillmore, Franklin Pierce, Abraham Lincoln, Andrew Johnson, Rutherford Hayes, Benjamin Harrison, William McKinely, Theodore Roosevelt, William Howard Taft, Woodrow Wilson, Warren G. Harding, Calivin Coolidge, Herbert Hoover, and Grover Cleveland. The collection also contains signatures of other influential historical figures, most notably those of Admiral Nelson, Napolean Bonaparte, Alexander Hamilton, and John Hancock.
Highlights from the collection include: documents relating to the Revolutionary War, documents relating to the Civil War, Society of Cincinnati certificates, the New York Loyalists' Address and the Loyalist Declaration of Dependence, Authorization for the Sale of Louisiana, Robert Fulton's steam engine drawings and ship drawings, Audubon bird descriptions and list, preliminary agreement and final contract between P.T. Barnum and Jenny Lind, signed copy of the Emancipation Proclamation, Kosciuszko drawings, and an execution warrant signed by George Washington.
Conditions Governing Access
Taking images of documents from the library collections for reference purposes by using hand-held cameras and in accordance with the library's photography guidelines is encouraged. As an alternative, patrons may request up to 20 images per day from staff.
Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to: Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024-5194, rightsandrepro@nyhistory.org. Phone: (212) 873-3400 ext. 282.
Copyrights and other proprietary rights may subsist in individuals and entities other than the New-York Historical Society, in which case the patron is responsible for securing permission from those parties. For fuller information about rights and reproductions from N-YHS visit: https://www.nyhistory.org/about/rights-reproductions
Arrangement
The Oversize Manuscripts Collection is organized into two Series: "Individual Oversize Manuscripts" and "Oversize Manuscripts From Other Collections". The materials located in Series I were donated or aquired individually and are organized into chronological order according to date. The materials described in Series II belong to other archival collections, but must be stored seperately due to their large size. These items are organized alphabetically by the name of the originating collection.
"Small" oversize folders are arranged in boxes, while "medium" and "large" oversize folders are stored in cabinet drawers.
Accruals Note
Items continue to be added to this collection.
Related Materials at the New-York Historical Society
The documents in Series II were accessioned as part of larger manuscript collections. Some of these manuscript collections are described in online finding aids. All manuscript collections have records in our online catalog.
Some of the documents in Series I are also related by subject matter (and possibly provenance) to other archival material at the New-York Historical Society. Folders in Series I that contain material relating to other collections have "See Also" notes next to them in the folder list.
Diplomas.; Presidents -- United States.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; Correspondence.; Real property -- New York (State) -- New York.; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783.; Historic buildings -- United States.; Historic sites -- United States.; Washington Square Park (New York, NY); Washington (D.C.); Warrants.; Virginia -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783.; Virginia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; Urban parks.; Upper class -- New York (State) -- New York.; United States -- History.; United States -- Politics and government.; Ulster County (N.Y.); Technical drawings.; Steam-engines -- Drawings.; Staten Island (New York, N.Y.); Soldiers.; Societies.; Slaves -- Emancipation.; Signatures (names); Ships -- United States.; Ships.; Shipbuilding.; Shipbuilding -- History.; Ships' logs.; Sheet music.; Riots -- New York (State); Registers (lists); Rationing -- United States.; Property records.; Prisoners -- New York (State); Presidential candidates -- United States.; Politicians.; Poems.; Petitions.; Payrolls.; Payroll records.; Patriotism.; Patents.; Passports.; Insurance.; Indians Of North America -- History.; Indentures.; History -- Societies, etc.; Genealogy.; Genealogies (histories); Financial documents.; Family.; Estate records.; Estate records.; Elections.; Certificates.; Deeds -- New York (State) -- Otsego County.; Burr-Hamilton Duel, Weehawken, N.J., 1804.; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Biology -- Classification -- Charts, diagrams, etc.; Autographs.; Armies -- Officers.; American loyalists -- New York (State) -- New York.; American loyalists.; Returns (military reports); Charts.; Circus performers -- United States.; City Hall Park (New York, N.Y.); Clubs -- New York (State) -- New York.; Commissions (orders for works).; Confederate States of America.; Decedents' estates.; Decedents' estates -- New York (State); Inventories.; Jails -- New York (State) -- New York.; Journals (accounts); Land grants.; Land grants -- New York (State); Land patents.; New York (State) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; Land titles -- New York (State); Land titles -- New York (State) -- Otsego County.; Deeds.; Ledgers (account books); Letters (correspondence); Manhattan (New York, N.Y.); Manuscripts (documents); Maps.; Marriage certificates.; Marriage -- New York (State).; Membership lists.; Military maneuvers.; United States -- Armed Forces -- Officers.; Military records.; Military service, Voluntary -- United States.; Military supplies -- New York (State); Military training camps -- United States.; Muster rolls.; Napoleonic Wars, 1800-1815.; New York (N.Y.) -- Societies, etc.; Clippings (information artifacts); New York (State) -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783.; Newspaper clippings.; Official documents.; Orders (military records); Parks.; Indians of North America.; Mohawk River Valley (N.Y.) -- History.; Andros, Edmund, Sir, 1637-1714; Audubon, John James, 1785-1851; Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co.; Ericsson, John, 1803-1889; Erving, John, 1789-1862; Fulton, Robert, 1765-1815 -- Exhibitions; Gates, Horatio, 1728-1806; King, Charles, 1789-1867; Lamb, Martha J. (Martha Joanna), 1829-1893 -- History of the City of New York; Lind, Jenny, 1820-1887 -- Portraits; McDougall, Alexander, 1732-1786; Shepard, Helen Miller Gould, 1868-1938; Thursby, Emma Cecilia, 1845-1931; United States. Continental Army -- Pay, allowances, etc.; United States. Continental Army -- Supplies and stores; Van Cortlandt (Family); Walton family; Washington, George, 1732-1799; Watts, John, 1749-1836; Watts family; White, Richard Grant, 1821-1885; Schuyler, Peter, 1657-1724
- Series I. Individual Oversize Manuscripts, 1648-1942
  - [Y-1648, April] Melyen Papers - Mandamus, 1648 April 28 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1648, April (Melyen))
    See Also:
    AHMC- Melyen, Cornelius
  - [Y-1651, January] Land Grant - Peter Stuyvesant to Manuel de Spangie, a free negro, 1651 January 18 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1651, January (Stuyvesant))
  - [Y-1667] Nicolls Richard Deed (Oversize small, Folder Y-1667 (Richard))
  - [Y-1672, May] John Howland Last Will and Testament, 1672 May 29 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1672, May (Howland))
  - [Y-1677, September] Andros- Oyster Bay- Deed, 1677 September 29 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1677, September (Andros))
  - [Y-1680, June] Andros Patent, 1680 June 4 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1680, June (Andros))
  - [Y-1685] Dongan's Patent - Queen's Village Manor (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1685 (Dongan))
  - [Y-1686] Dongan's Patent - Queen's Village Manor, 1685 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1686 (Dongan))
  - [Y-1686] Indian Deed (Oversize small, Folder Y-1686 (Deed))
  - [Y-1687, August] Dudley, Sloughton, Buckley- Court of Admiralty, 1687 August 18 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1687, August (Dudley))
  - [Y-1694, May] Lloyd Huddleston Deed, 1694 May 16 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1694, May (Huddleston))
  - [Y-1697] Petition of Cornelius Clausen (Oversize large, Folder Y-1697 (Clausen))
  - [Y-1700] Indenture for sale of land on Broadway in lower Manhattan to the Reformed Protestant Dutch Church of the City of New York, 1700-1701 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1700 (Indenture))
    Scope and Contents
    Parchment deed. Land sold by five couples, being the heirs of Pieter Stoutenburgh (1613-1699): Tobias Stoutenburgh (bricklayer) and wife, Antio (or Annetie?); Evort Boyvanko, Esquire and wife, Wyntio; Isaac Stoutenburgh (carpenter) and wife, Noltio; Albortus Ringo (cordwainer) and wife, Jannotio(?); and William Waldron and wife, Engoltio(?). Deed signed with seals by all, with three of the wives using marks. Deed recorded January 22, 1700. Later note on reverse signed by Justice David Provoost and others dated October 29, 1701. Rough typescript and notes from donor are also in the folder. (Gift of Dr. William O'Keefe, October 2019.)
  - [Y-1703] Commissions to Hilton by Dudley, 1703, 1704 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1703 (Dudley))
  - [Y-1704] New York Colony Accounts- Customs (Oversize small, Folder Y-1704 (New York Colony))
  - [Y-1704] Rensselaerswyck (Oversize large, Folder Y-1704 (Rensselaerswyck))
  - [Y-1704, May-June] Rensselaerswyck (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1704, May-June (Rensselaerswyck))
  - [Y-1704] Rensselaerswyck, 1704 June (Oversize small, Folder Y-1704, June (Rensselaerswyck))
  - [Y-1704, August] Petition to Queen Anne, 1704 August 28 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1704, August (Queen Anne))
  - [Y-1705] Customs Account, New York (Oversize small, Folder Y-1705 (Customs))
  - [Y-1705, April] Land Patent, 1705 April 19 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1705, April (Patent))
  - [Y-1706, April] Rutherfurd Collection- Small Scrapbook #32, 1706 April 5 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1706, April (Rutherfurd))
    Rutherfurd Collection
  - [Y-1708] Symes Patent (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1708 (Symes))
  - [Y-1708, March] Thomas Wenham, 1708 March 6 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1708, March (Wenham))
  - [Y-1708, September] Praa-Crommelin Deed, 1708 September 29 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1708, September (Praa-Crommelin))
  - [Y-1710, 1784] Deed and Military Appointment (Oversize large, Folder Y-1710, 1784)
    2 documents. Deed (1710) from Octavo Coemaats(?) to Abraham Wendell and sixteen others. Other surnames include Hooghlands(?), Hegeman, Beekman, Van Pelt, Van Dyk, Van Duyn, Cortelyou, Gouverneur, Volkertt(?), Veghten, and Van Leuwen(?). Deed is for property in the vicinity of the Raritan River and Millstone River in New Jersey. The second document is a 1784 certificate for the appointment of Arent Van Pelt as Second Lieutenant in Nicholas Van Brunt's Company in the regiment of militia in Kings County, New York. (The certificate's frame was removed and is boxed apart from the foldered document.)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift of Susan Wilson Bynum, 2017.
  - [Y-1712] Coroner's Inquests Re: 1712 Slave Revolt (Oversize small, Folder Y-1712 (Coroner))
  - [Y-1713, June] Indenture between Peter Schuyler and Hendrick Oothout, 1713 June 8 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1713, June (Schuyler))
  - [Y-1718, January] Deed- Abraham DePeyster to Samuel Bayard (Wall Street), 1718 January 3 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1718, January (DePeyster))
  - [Y-1718, May] Van Cortlandt Family- Deed, 1718 May 1 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1718, May (Van Cortlandt))
    Van Cortlandt Family Papers (1687-1831)
  - [Y-1718, May] Will of Henry Brevoort, 1718 May 4 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1718, May (Brevoort))
  - [Y-1718, July] Rutherfurd vol. 1, pg.11, 1718 July 2 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1718, July (Rutherfurd))
  - [Y-1718, September] Latham-Cannon Indenture, 1718 September 18 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1718, September (Latham-Cannon))
  - [Y-1720] Newkirk/Van Dam (Oversize small, Folder Y-1720 (Newkirk/Van Dam))
  - [Y-1720] Newkirk/Van Dam (Oversize large, Folder Y-1720 (Newkirk/Van Dam))
  - [Y-1720, March] Land Patent- Signed by Peter Schuyler, 1720 March 17 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1720, March (Schuyler))
  - [Y-1721] Land Deed b/w Anthony Holfaert and Rutgert Van Grunt (Oversize small, Folder Y-1721 (Holfaert))
  - [Y-1721, June] Indenture between Jacob Leisler and Francina Staats, 1721 June 19 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1721, June (Leisler))
  - [Y-1722, March] Verplanck Indenture, 1722 March 7 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1722, March (Verplanck))
  - [Y-1722, April] Johnston Lease and Release to Van Horne, 1722 April 16-17 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1722, April (Johnston))
  - [Y-1723] Deed of Partition of the Mohawk Lands (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1723 (Mohawk))
  - [Y-1723] Indenture between William and Jane Sell (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1723 (Sell))
  - [Y-1723, August] DuPuy- Malleville Indenture, 1723 August 9 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1723, August (DuPuy-Malleville))
  - [Y-1725] Deed of the Colony of Connecticut (Oversize small, Folder Y-1725 (Connecticut))
  - [Y-1727, February] Searle-Pintard Indenture, 1727 February 1 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1727, February (Searle-Pintard))
  - [Y-1732] Stephen Van Cortlandt (Oversize large, Folder Y-1732 (Van Cortlandt))
  - [Y-1732, October] Van Cortlandt Family- Deed, 1732 October 27 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1732, October (Van Cortlandt))
  - [Y-1733, August] Van Cortlandt Family- Chancery Deed, 1733 August 7 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1733, August (Van Cortlandt))
  - [Y-1733, November] Van Cortlandt Family Deeds, 1733 November 1-2 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1733, November 1-2 (Van Cortlandt))
  - [Y-1733, November] Van Cortlandt Family- Deed, 1733 November 12 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1733, November 12 (Van Cortlandt))
  - [Y-1734] Lewis Morris Court Case Argued in London (Oversize small, Folder Y-1734 (Morris))
  - [Y-1735, July] Charter of the St. George's Church, Hempstead, Long Island, 1735 July 23 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1735, July (Hempstead))
  - [Y-1735, December] Indian Deed- Westenhook, 1735 December 24 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1735, December (Westenhook))
  - [Y-1736, May] Probate, Will of Theophilus Elsworth, 1736 May 24 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1736, May (Elsworth))
  - [Y-1742] Partition of the Stuyvesant Estate (Oversize large, Folder Y-1742 (Stuyvesant))
    John Rutherfurd papers, 1726-1835 (bulk 1775-1835); Harlem papers, 1660-1879 (bulk [before 1800])
  - [Y-1742, April] Ann Pritchard- Writ, 1742 April 17 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1742, April (Pritchard- Writ))
  - [Y-1742, December] Indenture- Van Borssom Remsen, 1742 December 17 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1742, December (Remsen))
  - [Y-1743, June] Exemplification of Land Patents of Robert Livingston, 1743 June 1 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1743, June (Livingston))
  - [Y-1744, May] Malleville-DeWint Deed, 1744 May 18 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1744, May (Malleville))
  - [Y-1744, September] Appointment of James Delancey- Chief Justice, 1744 September 14 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1744, September (Delancey))
  - [Y-1745, February, March] Lease and Release- James Van Horne to Abraham Lodge- Lots in Dock Ward, New York City, 1745 February 28, March 3 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1745, February (Horne))
  - [Y-1745, March] Lodge, Abraham- Conveyance to Van Horne (Two Lots- Dock Ward- NYC), 1745 March 17 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1745, March (Lodge))
  - [Y-1745, June] Bayard to Kennedy- Deeds, 1745 June 7-8 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1745, June (Bayard))
  - [Y-1745, September] Levy, Isaac, Inventory (Oversize small, Folder Y-1745, September (Levy))
  - [Y-1747] Van Cortlandt Family - Patent for Dutch Church (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1747 (Van Cortlandt))
  - [Y-1747] Ludlow, John and William (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1747 (Ludlow))
  - [Y-1747, October] Appointment of James Delancey- Lieutenant Governor of New York, 1747 October 27 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1747, October (Delancey))
  - [Y-1748, October] Probate of John Cannon's Will, 1748 October 5 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1748, October (Cannon))
  - [Y-1749, June] Van Cortlandt Family- Agreement, 1749 June 12 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1749, June (Van Cortlandt))
  - [Y-1749, December] Alexander vs. Timothy Meeker (Alexander Papers), 1749 December 1 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1749, December (Alexander))
    Alexander papers, 1668-1818 (bulk 1717-1786)
  - [Y-1753] Deed and Map- Cooper Property- Oyster Bay, L.I. (Oversize small, Folder Y-1753 (Cooper))
  - [Y-1753, February] Letters Patent of George the Second to Van Cortlandt, 1753 February 19 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1753, February (Van Cortlandt))
    Van Cortlandt family papers, 1688-1846
  - [Y-1758] Commission to Try Pirates (Oversize large, Folder Y-1758 (Pirates))
  - [Y-1759, March] Montgomery Ward- Lease, 1759 March 29 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1759, March (Montgomery))
  - [Y-1760, October] Broadside (From Colden Papers), 1760 October 27 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1760, October (Colden))
    Cadwallader Colden Papers, 1677-1832 (bulk 1711-1775)
  - [Y-1761, May] Muster Roll, 1761 May 19 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1761, May (Muster))
  - [Y-1761, May] White and Crawford Patent, 1761 May 13 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1761, May (White))
  - [Y-1762, January] Van Ranst- Deed, 1762 January 3 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1762, January (Van Ranst))
  - [Y-1763] Yates, Christopher- Mohawk River- Canajoharie Patent (Oversize small, Folder Y-1763 (Yates))
  - [Y-1763] Maershalk Map (From Henry Barclay and Family Land Papers) (Oversize large, Folder Y-1763 (Barclay))
    Henry Barclay and family land papers, 1764-1834
  - [Y-1763, January] Rapalje- Deed, 1763 January 22 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1763, January (Rapalje))
  - [Y-1765] Deed of Conveyance for Land in Nassau b/w Denys and Crepser (Oversize small, Folder Y-1765 (Nassau))
  - [Y-1766] North Carolina (From Bv North Carolina Hawks Papers) (Oversize small, Folder Y-1766 (Hawks))
    Francis L. Hawks papers, 1833-1866
  - [Y-1766, May] Sons of Liberty, 1766 May 31 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1766, May (Sons))
  - [Y-1768] Indenture b/w George and Cary Ludlow (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1768 (Ludlow))
  - [Y-1768, May] Lupton, Swits, Schuyler Indenture, 1768 May 16 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1768, May (Lupton))
  - [Y-1769, March] Rivington, Van Horne, McEvers- Tripartite Agreement, 1769 March 8 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1769, March (Rivington))
  - [Y-1769, March] Rivington, Van Horne, McEvers- Tripartite Agreement, 1769 March 8 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1769, March (Rivington))
  - [Y-1769, March] Remsen, 1769 March 18 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1769, March (Remsen))
  - [Y-1769, April] Staats Long Morris Release, 1769 April 4 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1769, April (Morris))
  - [Y-1769, May] DeLancey Deed, 1769 May 5 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1769, May (DeLancey))
  - [Y-1769, September] Charter, 1769 September 29 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1769, September (Charter))
  - [Y-1771] Petition to Lord Dunmore (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1771 (Dunmore))
  - [Y-1771, March] Kayaderosseras Patent [Field] book (Oversize small, Folder Y-1771, March (Kayaderosseras))
  - [Y-1771, June] N.Y. Hospital- Charter, 1771 June 13 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1771, June (N.Y. Hospital))
  - [Y-1772, December] Beekman Family- Deed, 1772 December 1 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1772, December (Beekman))
    Beekman Family Papers
  - [Y-1773, February] Farmer, Samuel- Deed, 1773 February 2 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1773, February (Samuel))
  - [Y-1773, March] Poughkeepsie, N.Y., 1773 March 9 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1773, March (Poughkeepsie))
  - [Y-1773, March] Charter of Christ Church- Poughkeepsie, N.Y., 1773 March 9 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1773, March (Christ Church))
  - [Y-1773, May] Kayaderosseras Patent [Field] Book (Oversize small, Folder Y-1773, May (Kayaderosseras))
  - [Y-1774] Verplanck, Samuel- Deeds (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1774 (Verplanck))
  - [Y-1774, March] Deed- Flushing, 1774 March 26 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1774, March (Flushing))
  - [Y-1774, April] Waldron, Adolph- Ferry Lease, 1774 April 12 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1774, April (Waldron))
  - [Y-1774, May] Facsimile- Letter from New York to Massachusetts, 1774 May 23 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1774, May (Facsimile))
  - [Y-1774, October] Varick, Richard- Attorney at Law, 1774 October 21 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1774, October (Varick))
  - [Y-1774-1775] Remsen Invoice Book (Oversize small, Folder Y-1774 (Remsen))
  - [Y-1775, August] Beekman Release, 1775 August 11 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1775, August (Beekman))
  - [Y-1776, February] Watts, Robert and John- Deed, 1776 February 20 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1776, February (Watts))
  - [Y-1776] New York Loyalists Address to Lord and General Howe and Sir Tryon, 948 Signers (a.k.a. Black List, Tory List) (Oversize small, Folder Y-1776 (Howe))
  - [Y-1776, November] Loyalist Declaration of Dependence- Photostat Copy with Photos, 1776 November 28 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1776, November (Loyalist, Copy))
  - [Y-1776, November] The New York Loyalist Declaration of Dependence, 1776 November 28 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1776, November (Loyalist))
  - [Y-1777] Enlistment Roll, 1st Ind. Co. NY Rangers (MM Benson), circa 1777 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1777 (Benson))
  - [Y-1777, July] Return of Ordinance and Stores at Ticonderoga (Gates Papers), 1777 July 4 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1777, July (Gates))
    Horatio Gates Papers (1750-1780)
  - [Y-1779] Order of Battle, etc.- Sullivan's Expedition (Swartwout Papers) (Oversize small, Folder Y-1779 (Swartwout))
    Barnardus Swartwout papers, 1777-1783, 1824
  - [Y-1779-1780] Drawings of General Stark's Brigade's Winter Quarters Near West Point (Oversize small, Folder Y-1779 (Stark's Brigade))
  - [Y-1779, 1780] Letters of Marque and Reprisal, 1779 February 9; 1780 May 17 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1779 February (Marque, Reprisal))
  - [Y-1780] Waggon Dept. Returns (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1780 (Waggon))
  - [Y-1782] Nelson, Horatio- Letter and Illustration (Oversize small, Folder Y-1782 (Nelson))
  - [Y-1783] Return of Officers Entitled to Draw Forage (Oversize small, Folder Y-1783 (Forage))